Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Hello, good evening, good day everybody
and welcome to ask Abijit this special
60inute episode. I apologize I could not
do an episode yesterday. The noise
levels where I am were too high so there
was no point doing it. It would have
been a headache for me as well as for
you. So here we are today. This is a
special episode to make up for that and
maybe we can do one more tomorrow if
it's if you would like that. So let us
see who all is there on the live chat
with all of us. I can see Vladimir Putin
Aush Singh Himmanu Rajit Bruce Wayne is
here. Bruce Wayne from Gotham City. Uh,
Himmanshu Rajhit Rasputin. Hello. Gorish
KB AJ Rahul. Patriotic, Arya, Kash,
Suman, Shakhar, Sarangi, Shivam, Shukla,
Rasputin again, Anonymous, Stein Talks,
Dharma, Dak, Gorish, KBI, Akash,
Patwartan, Adwi, Many, Vidy, Mña,
Geopolitical Dub, Amish, Mishra, Aayush
Singh, Rishab, Uchiah, White, Mahik,
Kata, Shivasai, Raghav, Malotra,
Godliness, Ashok, Geopolitical Dubai
from Indor, Vinay from London, Raghav
Malotra, Bharat, Mayang,
Frame player unknown vnu moan navin sai
vimuri patriotic polar bear is here
bharat again suraj s
bhargav gowami dik shrian himanchu d
from kolinga well hello
shhated bagel
and lots of other people all right all
right it's so nice to see you allam
singing prahit Anupam Singh Anupam
Pratab Singh sorry from LinkedIn
and Annie Annie is there Prii Sudartik
Hardik Jooshi Kanesh Koshik and
everybody else all right let's get going
with the questions uh let's take as many
questions as possible I can see Sy
Mahmud Ucho hello and everyone else RPPL
from Washington DC is has joined us
Himmano is from Chennai and so on all
right let's get going with the questions
what questions do we have godliness says
Trump is frustrated with Ukraine,
Russia, with India and China. Do you
believe out of this frustration he will
use US military might in the future to
reestablish the American supremacy? And
if yes, in which region?
Well, the people he's frustrated with
are people that are not that amable to,
you know, being being uh being
intimidated by military might. So if
Trump is frustrated with Ukraine and
Russia, well Ukraine is his war. It's
not Putin's war or Modi's war. It's an
American war. They created this war. The
Americans. So they've been blaming Putin
for this all the time. It's Putin's war.
Putin started this. No, you forced him
into it. They forced Putin. They forced
Russia into this by crossing by crossing
Russia's red lines.
It's like uh imagine if Russia goes and
interferes in in Mexico and starts doing
a regime change operation in Mexico or
in Canada. Will the Americans allow it?
It will be a red line for the Americans.
They did the same thing in Russia in in
Ukraine which was a Russian red line and
it directly impacts Russia's national
security and which is why the war has
happened. It is an American war and
Ukraine is merely a proxy. So it's it's
an American war. It's essentially US
versus Russia by proxy. And if he is
frustrated, Trump is frustrated with
that. Well, that's not anyone's problem.
He had it it is a trap that he laid
himself by claiming that he would end
the war on day one. Well, it's been
months now. What happened to your
promise to the American citizen that he
would end the Ukraine war on day one?
It's a failure. Trump has failed. He's
immensely frustrated and he's trying to
blame people for that. His his minion
Navaro is saying this is Modi's war. Oh,
really? Should India withdraw the troops
from Donbas? Should we? Please, please
let us know if we should withdraw our
Indian troops from the Donbas region.
Would you like us to do that? What? I
these people are delusional. They're
lashing out at the world. They're
blaming others for their own for for
problems they have created themselves.
So yes, Trump is frustrated. He's
frustrated about the Ukraine situation.
He's frustrated with Russia because
Russia hasn't crumbled. He's frustrated
about India because India hasn't caved
in to his uh bullying. And he's
frustrated with China because China has
become a powerful nation. and the
technological genuine technological
power which is almost neck-to- neck with
the US in his frustration will the US
use military might it'll be a huge
mistake to use to try and use military
might anywhere u I mean for to use
military might somewhere you need a just
cause for war right I mean you can go
and bully small nations like Venezuela
and all it won't work with the more
powerful nations uh the US supremacy is
still there I mean they have immense
power production capac probabilities.
They have uh uh they have a legion of
vasals all across the world. The entire
EU NATO nations are their vasals. All
the African nations are in in the US's
thr Japan, South Korea, many Southeast
Asian nations unfortunately are under
the US domination. So they already have
supremacy. They Australia is under the
supremacy. New Zealand, uh Latin
America, all of that. So it's not like
they don't have supremacy but they
they're frustrated because their power
is kind of declining and you can they
can see other powers rising now. So I
don't see the Americans uh using
military might. They may use proxies.
They may use Pakistan to create a war
with India. They will first aim they
will first arm Pakistan.
See we we saw what happened in operation
Sindur. Pakistan got a tremendous
hammering. No matter what the western
media is saying and the Pakistani media
is saying and some sections of the
Indian media are saying we know the
Pakistanis got a hammering. So the
Americans will have identified what are
the Pakistani weaknesses and they will
try and fill those weaknesses with
American weapons and whatnot. It may be
happening as we speak right now and when
they feel the time is right they may
start a war with India through Pakistan
to create a Ukraine like situation for
us. That's one thing they could do for
China. Well, I don't see much that they
can do unless they want South Korea or
Japan to go to war with China, which
won't happen, which is not possible. So,
with China, it's not possible. With
Russia, they've already created the
Ukraine situation. With India, they may
create a Pakistan situation. So, that is
something we have to be cognizant of. In
the future, in the coming days, weeks,
months, the US may trigger an
IndiaPakistan war. They may ask the
Pakistanis to go to war with India by by
maybe creating a pahelam 2.0 kind of
situation, right? So yeah that that the
Americans could do but apart from that
direct military intervention I don't see
that happening.
Uh says don't you think that the a small
tusidi trap applies for the US visa
versus ASEAN because if they get too
powerful they can use the leverage of
our dependency with with respect to
China. No thusidaris trap occurs between
peer competitors. It doesn't happen with
vasals.
Unfortunately,
Assean nations are kind of are kind of
US allies or US vasals. Okay. In in
various ways, economic means, other
means, there's no chance of a thusid
trap happening between the overlord and
his vasals. Unless the vasals start
becoming genuine powers in their own
right, which is not happening any
anyway. Which is not happening. Yeah.
How is Assan going to become too
powerful? A little bit of economic might
doesn't make any difference. Power. What
does what is what does powerful mean? It
means genuine military power and power
projection capabilities. And if it's
economic might, it's the kind of
economic might that can transform the
world. So even India doesn't have that
right now. But India could be there in
the next 15 20 years. And that's why the
Americans are worried about India.
Assan. No.
Vidi says deep state low key uniting
Jamudas. So goat FR. Yes.
Yeah,
Amisha says, "What are your conclusions
from the SEO summit?" It's kind of a
reset reset in the India China
relationship. Mr. Putin will be pleased
about that. And uh it's it's a signal to
to the to to Mr. Trump essentially that
your bullying is not going to work with
certain nations. It's not going to work
with India. It's not going to work with
Russia or with China. And uh you can see
that now Trump's antics, Trump's
theatrics and Trump's trade war against
the world, it is creating a coalition of
the nations that are being targeted and
India and China are willing to once
again engage perhaps constructively.
We'll have to see about that. But you
can definitely see a reset in the India
China relationship. Mr. Modi and Mr.
Xiinping met face to face across the
table in a proper formal uh
meeting and they also interacted with
Mr. the Putin and all all that and the
the visuals were very positive, very
very very friendly, very warm visuals.
So overall you could say you could you
could say that it's a reset. It's maybe
uh the beginning of something new
perhaps possibly uh I think it's still
too too early to say whether an RA kind
of thing would happen. on Russia, India,
China that sort of coalition or alliance
I think it's too early for that to to
predict that but you can definitely see
a reset and uh yeah so overall it's it's
a good signs for the free world the free
world what's the free world the free
world is the world which is not
vasalized by the US so it's it's good
science for the free world
uh feminist says importance of PSUs
public sector units in India's
sovereignty
Everything is is important in India
sovereignty. All the uh all the sectors,
all the units whether they're public,
whether they're private, they are all in
in some way or the other important for
maintaining India's economic and overall
overall sovereignty. PSUs well these are
these are industries or or or businesses
that are essentially run by the
government and uh historically they have
been well not performing so well. So I'm
not sure about that. But overall
everything is important in India's
sovereignty. India India India's economy
needs to be well it needs to be robust
and everything well uh everything
contributes to that including PSUs.
Shankar Mahadevan says was Trump's
crypto business hit in Pakistan well
Trump hasn't really started his crypto
business in Pakistan right um he had
announced well see he's not directly
involved with the com with the Trump
empire companies that are investing in
Pakistan directly means uh he his son or
sons or family members are running the
running the show but obviously it's his
business empire and they have recently
invested ed in a big way in Pakistan's
cryptocurrency sector. Was that hit? I
have not seen any signs of that being
hit because the cryptocurrency sector
hasn't even taken off in Pakistan.
That's something the Americans will be
investing in. That's what the Trump
empire will be investing in in the
coming well coming time.
Okay. Uh says US means India. US means
India in what?
Uh okay. US means India. All right. uh
pjari says is ra bigger victory for
China than India ra hasn't happened
first of all and if ra happens it will
depend on what what form of ra happens
what's the shape of ra what's the
contours of ra what's the agreements and
understandings that underpin the ra that
will decide whether it's a big victory
for China or India or Russia or it's
good for everybody everybody at the same
time ra hasn't happened what does ra
mean it's It it's it means it's an RA
essentially means Russia, India, China
cooperating, collaborating together,
perhaps an alliance or perhaps just a
coalition.
Um so it hasn't happened yet. It's the
Shang the SEO meeting was just
essentially a reset. It's the three
leaders coming together um and uh
showing that they are willing to work
together especially India and China that
was important. So now we'll have to see
how it is taken forward.
That is what's going to matter. So how
do India and China sit together and work
things out? We have major differences,
major issues, right? The border issue is
a very major issue and as long as that
fers the relationship cannot be on the
on the right track. So what do we do
about that? So RA hasn't happened yet
and whenever RA if it does happen when
it happens we will have to see what is
the shape of RA. Is it is it a treaty?
Is it an RC treaty in which the three
nations officially
create a treaty and and sign it and
decide and and and agree to work
together in a specific set of ways? If
that is the case, then we'll have to
examine the nature of the treaty. What
what is the language of the treaty? What
is what has been agreed upon? If there
is no treaty, if it is just an informal
thing, well, then that's not really RA.
See, so it's too early to say that RA
has even happened. And then if RA
happens then we'll have to see whether
it's a victory for one or the other or
all three. We'll have to see about that.
It's too early. It's too early to talk
about RA.
Uh geopolitical Dubai says how strong is
the Russian presence in Central Asia?
Russia considers Central Asia to be its
strategic backyard like India has the
slogan, right? We consider the Indian
Ocean region to be our strategic
backyard. Well, Russia has it's more
than a slogan for Russia. They see the
central Asian region used to be part of
the USSR. So everybody there speaks
essentially speaks Russian. Now after
the USSR broke up there have been new
generations that have been born which
have not been that that Russianized
as such. Uh but the Russian influence is
still very strong and Russia has all
kinds of agreements with various
nations. Some are military cooperation
agreements, some are bilateral
agreements of economic, some are uh uh
defense agreements and so on. So Russia
engages in in in bilateral and
multilateral military exercises and
other things with all these nations. So
Russia has a significant presence in the
region. Russia still acts as a guaranter
of power or guaranter of security for
these nations for many of these nations.
Some of the nations have been
dillydallying with the US. Some of them
have been doing that. For example, if
you look at Kygystan, okay, I'm just
giving one example. Kygystan, there is
an American university there in Bishk.
Bishkek is the capital of Kyrgystan. And
there is a AUCA there. American
University of Central Asia. So the
Americans have infiltrated places like
Kyrgystan. They have even uh created
color revolutions in some of these
countries. But still overall Russia has
a pretty strong very robust and pretty
strong presence in various central Asian
nations. And uh there are certain red
lines these central Asian nations
essentially cannot cross when it comes
to uh uh you know not displeasing
Russia.
Karishka says any update on Tibet as
India and China are cooperating a bit
it's it's there is no update on Tibet
what do you expect what can we expect do
you think that Tibet will now suddenly
become jointly governed by India and
China
is that what anyone is expecting
there's no update on Tibet even if India
and China cooperate more than a bit
there's going to be no update on Tibet
Tibet is a non-negotiable thing for
China is not giving up Tibet Okay.
So, yeah, there is no update on Tibet.
Nothing. Absolutely nothing. None. You
don't even dream of it.
Project Smiling Buddha says, uh, many
Indian right-wing people have turned
many Indian right-wing people turned
pro- US ditched India.
I'm not sure exactly what you're asking,
but I kind of get get what you're
saying. See, when Trump came to power,
there's so many Indians who are like
celebrating. So I hear that somebody
even made a temple to Trump and put a
Morty of Trump there and they're
worshiping the guy that sort of thing.
Lots of Indians are saying that these
are the glory days of India US that sort
of thing. Yeah. Uh
um and and you can see that this has
been the worst ever presidency American
presidency for India. No American
president, no American regime has ever
used this much economic co coercion
against India. Not even the Nixon
Kissinger regime co tried to coers India
in the way that the Trump regime has
done. This is the worst phase of India
US relations ever since 1947. Right. U
so what happened to all those people? I
think they they're staying quiet. Have
they ditched India? I have no idea who
has ditched India. If you're Indian, how
do you ditch India? Yeah, if you're
Indian, you can ditch India by migrating
to the US and becoming a citizen. That's
what you can do. U but yeah overall
those who were celebrating well they're
quiet now I suppose
and project smiling Buddha says why are
Indian businesses not selling in Russia
as much we just came back last week from
Russia and sold a lot of tea spices from
Pakistan and Sri Lanka but not India
well I don't know
I mean if Pakistan and Sri Lanka are
selling tea and spices in Russia why
isn't India doing a thing I think India
is really there's a lot India needs to
do about this I mean India seems to be
very lacks in this in this matter.
Little countries are getting ahead of
India in certain ways. India should be
monopolizing tea, spices, all of that in
Russia. There should be no place for for
Pakistan or Sri Lanka. I don't know why
it's like this. We are a way bigger
manufacturer of tea and spices and whatn
not everything else compared to Pakistan
or Sri Lanka. So I think the Indian
government and the government of India
needs to needs to look into this very
carefully. What on earth is happening?
Are we dozing at the wheel?
Yeah, I don't know. I I I don't have the
answer to this. Why are not Indian
businesses not selling so much in
Russia?
And when it comes to manufacturing, when
is the Indian manufacturing sector
taking off? All of this needs to be tak
looked into now. Now is a very critical
time for India. India is under immense
pressure from the US. The Indian economy
is going to be hit by the by the Trump
tariffs. Okay. There's going to be hit
of 0.6 to 0.8%. That's what being what
is being projected by by various experts
over the next year at least as long as
the uh san or not sanctions the tariffs
continue. So it is high time for India
to to throw away its its lethargy its
laziness and uh take these things very
seriously.
So yeah, I would say that uh it's good
that you're you're pointing this out and
this is something that needs to be uh
looked into and worked upon on a urgent
priority basis.
Dins says would you personally accept
Axai as part of China if China forfeits
their claim to Arunachal? Do you think
both countries can agree on this?
You see that's the problem. That's the
problem. I can personally say I can
agree to this or that. But if imagine
you're asking this to the prime minister
of India the moment the prime minister
of India let's say hypothetically
hypothetically fictitiously agrees to
some sort of thing like this h
what's going to happen the opposition is
going to go to the top of every rooftop
and every mountain and start tomtoming
see he sold our country to China that's
what they'll claim it is they who sold
the country to China by allowing the
Chinese to take succession in the first
place but now if we on paper recognize
it and agree to a swap. Then the
opposition will will try and go for
blood. This is the problem. The what is
the deeper problem? The fact that this
country is a democracy. Yeah. Where
where random people can decide the the
fate of the government based on emotive
issues, emotional things. Would I
personally accept Axai Chain as part of
China if China forfeits that claim to
Arunach?
Me personally, I think I may I may
accept that as a temporary measure.
Eventually, I want everything back. But
right now, I'll say sure. Okay. Right
now, let's agree to this. Later, we'll
see.
Maybe I would do that because right now
it's anyway in their hands, right? So,
and Arunachal is in our hands. So I
think the cleanest way to settle the the
the boundary issue the India Tibet
boundary issue is to freeze the boundary
wherever it is and and declare it the
international border. I think that's the
cleanest way to do it. That would end
all the problems. But uh I can say it
sitting here because nobody I don't need
anyone's votes. Okay. But if you're the
prime minister of India, you need votes
otherwise next uh election you're out.
So that's the problem in India. That's
the problem.
Rahul G says, "Will China still trade
weapons with Pakistan?" That remains to
be seen, right? They haven't told us.
They haven't told us. We still have no
agreement with China. It's just been a
nice reset kind of to some extent that
the two leaders can now sit face to face
and talk to each other and and walk walk
around the hall with Mr. Putin smiling.
That is a major major change that's
happened. Earlier the two leaders did
not even look at each other. They did
not even meet each other for several
years. So that is the extent of the
reset. It doesn't mean that you know now
now everything has changed and China
will no longer sell weapons to Pakistan.
They may still do it. That's the thing.
So we still have to see what the
situation is.
Um what will most likely happen now is
that the the the um diplomats of the two
countries, leaders of the two countries
at at various levels will sit together
and try and understand what can be done
going forward. What do you seek from us?
What do I seek from you? Let's
understand each other's perspective.
What is that? What is it that you want
from me? And what is it that you would
what is it that you don't like that I'm
doing? How would you like what kind of
change do you want? And I can tell you
what kind of change I want. So if I'm
India, I'll tell tell the Chinese, look,
you need to stop dealing with Pakistan.
Okay? You need to stop selling weapons
to Pakistan. What if if if that's what
we want, what would you like from us in
return? So they'll say something about
the Dalai Lama, they'll say something
about something else. So So you to go
get down, sit together
and and talk everything through,
understand very well what what the other
guy wants. They have to understand very
well what we want. And then there has to
be some kind of understanding and some
kind of agreement. And a good agreement
is something in which both have to make
some compromise. So right now it's too
early to say. I think China will still
be inclined to I think China will still
be inclined to sell Pakistan some
weapons. I think so.
Anything UV says
how and when India can have labs like
Bell Labs or Deep Mind IMB research? Why
do we lack such institutions from the
government and private players? It's
because most of the money in India the
government money goes into freebies
funding freebies all these all these
various schemes freebie schemes which
keep the votes coming because see you
see you have to understand this India as
a democracy and in India the the
most people are uneducated just having
passed a certain standard 10th standard
12 standard maybe college doesn't mean
that you you have an understanding of
the world you you don't you're not
taught how to think critically you don't
you're not taught what it means to be
genuinely self-sufficient, right? So
most people still want all these
freebies despite having some sort of
education. And if the government ends
the freebie schemes,
then they will stop then they will the
the people will not vote for them.
Whoever ends all these all these free
things that are being given, they will
be voted out out of power immediately.
So all of the money of of the country a
lot of it is being spent on these
largely bahhana yojas and god knows what
yojas I don't know what it does yeah but
whatever
so when you have so much money being
spent like that how will you have all
these things you know bell labs deep
mind whatever and when it comes to the
private players when the private players
only want to make some money
money
They are happy with a few crores, maybe
a few hundred crores, maybe know a few
thousand crores. They don't know to
think about the trillions of dollars
that you can earn by really investing in
in genuine hardcore cutting edge
bleeding edge research for many years
and being patient,
right? They want the money now and it's
easy to make money now by playing the
game of labor arbitrage or whatever. So
that's why that's the issue in India.
It's it's a mindset issue. There are
young people who are coming up now with
starters startups and all who are really
investing in a small way in genuine
research and those hopefully in the
years in coming years will become really
big going forward. So that's what one
hopes
basal
says demographic re-engineering in
Europe by Ghar Raj deep state and so on.
What's the reason for that? Is it only
because Christianity has reduced so much
that they need new ways of control or is
it something more? Uh
yeah, I mean I'm sure there's multiple
factors behind this. See, there is no
question about the fact that there is
demographic re-engineering happening in
Europe as we speak every country and uh
whether you look at France. Well, the
French are responsible for what happened
in France themselves by first colonizing
North Africa and then having so much
immigration coming from North Africa
that now France is like a multi-thnic
country and uh so the French are
responsible for their own plight. When
it comes to nations like the Nordic
nation, Sweden, Denmark, Norway, there's
a lot of immigration from from specific
countries that's happened in the past
1015 years. So much that the whole
demography has changed. You're seeing
that in Ireland now. It started just a
few years ago like four five years ago
and now already you can see a major
major change. I mean Dublin one here is
the center of Dublin looks very
different now. England they are
responsible for their own PL but overall
if you look at it there is
re-engineering of the demography
happening. Certain kinds of people are
being pushed in in large numbers. So the
question is why? Who is doing it and
why? Look it is all being done by the
EU. The EU has refugee quotas or
immigrant quotas for every country and
every country has to allow every year a
certain number of immigrants in. And who
decides the kind of immigrants? I think
the EU decides what what countries the
immigrants can come from. It's usually
military-aged males, young males and
very few women or children. So that's
what they're doing. They're bringing in
these people. It's essentially an
invasion that is being engineered by the
EU. Now the EU is controlled from
Washington DC. The EU is a bunch of
bureaucrats that nobody elected and
they're all controlled from the US. So
it's all being done in some way or other
through the US by the US. Uh so you
could say the deep state is behind it.
What's the reasons? Is it because uh
Christianity has reduced? Uh
it's it's true that of late the past
several decades Christianity has really
gone down. I mean where the number of
practicing Christians has reduced
drastically. uh in the 1980s when the
pope would visit Ireland there would be
millions of peoples on people on the
street out there to take a to catch a
glimpse of the pope but uh now if the
pope visits there the pope will not even
bother to go on on on that in that car
in public you know because no one's
going to turn up to see the pope so the
number of practicing Christians has
reduced drastically because of various
factors uh and Christianity historically
in in the west has been uh tool of
control. The entire populace of Europe
historically was controlled through
Christianity
rather Christianity has been well
essentially overthrown in in in a
variety of ways. So how do you control
the people right? Uh so so you can bring
in a new religion which also is the
religion of control and maybe you can do
it that way. So re-engineer the
religious demographics of the country,
re-engineer the ethnic demographics of
the country and then control everyone
through this new religion. That's one
hypothesis that one could put forward,
right? Uh and another thing I mean when
it comes to nations like Germany, so
Germany was well it it it aspired to be
great. They've always had this this uh
ideal of the white race. uh sometime in
the 19th century they they they stole
the the word Arya from India and they
decided that that the word Arya or Arian
means white people that's what they
decided unilaterally by stealing our
ethnic selfd designation
so Germany aspired to be great and their
their ideal of greatness was the Arian
race the white race so-called white race
it's completely fake but whatever so
Germany is that sort of nation that the
Americans are afraid of The Americans
worry about Germany that Germany could
once again rise someday if the right
leader comes up and once again you could
have the whole rigma roll that happened
in the 1930s and 40s. So how do you
ensure it doesn't happen? See whenever
the Americans think of Germany at some
some level in their mind in their psyche
they can still see those marching boots
the Reich matching marching boots they
don't want to see that again. So how do
you ensure it never happens again? end
the the the the the
Arian race, have them mix with all kinds
of immigrants from everywhere else. So
there's no question of the superior race
or anything. The German identity itself
disappears, right? So yeah, so that's
that's one way of ensuring that Germany
never rises again because it won't be
Germany eventually. It will no longer
remain Germany if uh so many people from
other countries come in a lot of Turks
the there's been a bunch of Turks in
Germany for for decades. since the end
of the second world war essentially uh I
don't know what percentage of Germany is
is is of Turkish ethnicity maybe close
to 10%. And then you bring in other
people from uh specific countries and
you and you change the demography even
more and uh you have the government uh
promote
these these multicultural ideas and all
that and whatever. So that way you can
essentially destroy
what it means to be German, the German
identity itself. you can simply erase it
over over a few generations. So I think
that's that's what's going on. It's to
ensure that Europe never rises again.
And if you want to control the people of
Europe, you turn them into non-Europeans
over time. And then you use the new
religion that's now been uh been
implanted there to control the people.
It's all about control. The West has
always been about control, control,
centralized control. Uh so that's what's
going on again. It's it's a phase of
European history which will end with
Europe no longer being Europe. Well,
Kanesh Kakoshik says, "I don't know
where's my brahminical profit from
Russian oil." I know. I know. Pete
Navaro has gone crazy. He's he's an
absolute imbecile. Trump's minion. Pete
Navaro. He went on TV, American TV, and
said that the brahinss in India are
profiting from oil, from Russian oil.
What?
Who is this utter
He he went on TV and claimed that
Brahinss in India are profiting from
Russian oil. This is desperation. This
is utter lunacy, idiocy.
This is I mean I don't know what polite
word I can dredge out of my mind to to
describe this individual Pete Navaro.
And whatever he's saying is Trump's
words. It's his mouth and his lips that
are fluttering, but it's Trump's words
that are coming out. Brahminical profit.
Yeah. So in India, the Brahminss are
profiting from Russian oil. Ukraine is a
nation that's buying Indian diesel that
is refined from Russian oil. So is
Ukraine funding Putin's war on Ukraine?
Is that is that the case? These people
in the US, what is wrong with them?
Trump has the thing about Trump is that
he has hired a a bunch of yesmen.
These yesmen, they wake up in the
morning, go to the White House, lie down
at his feet and kiss his kiss his shoes.
That's what they do.
They are yesmen. They will do whatever
Trump says. They are not picked for
their intellect or for their for their
qualities or their capabilities. They
are picked for being yesmen. Just do
what I say and that's it. And JD Vance
finds himself in a very tough position
right now. So that's the kind of
nonsense that's that's coming out of the
US right now that Brahmans in India are
making profits from Russian oil.
Absolute bunch of idiots.
Naman Singh says let's think
hypothetically. How can India move
towards stability dictatorship OPR?
What's OPR? One party rule. Oh uh and
how can we ensure the growth of India
avoiding the curse opposition? I I don't
know. I I have no idea how that happens.
See right now everything
Yeah. How do you do move towards a one
party system? Uh for that to happen, one
party will have to make all other
parties irrelevant in some way, which
means that the the public no longer
votes for the other parties. And then
you have de facto one party rule because
then the opposition becomes essentially
non-existent.
But in in the Indian system currently,
you can only have this happen through
the process of democracy. There's no
other way it happens. India is not the
kind of country where you could have a
military coup. It's not that kind of
country. It just won't happen. It just
won't work even if it's attempted. Yeah.
Uh it doesn't work. If a military coup
happens, then they can only control the
building that they are controlling.
That's that's how it goes in India. It
doesn't work. Uh Raheem change. Well,
yeah, that so the thing is how how can
India move towards that? it in the
current shape of things the way it is
the only way to achieve that is through
the democratic process it's by one party
becoming so powerful and so popular in
the public eye that all other parties no
longer get any any meaningful votes and
you have a deep de facto one party rule
and that's how uh you can ensure the
growth of India and avoid this this
headache of u look in a democracy an
opposition actually should be valuable
If the government is not doing some
things right that they should point it
out and and and point it out to the
people and force the government to do
the right things. But sometimes you have
situations in some countries okay
hypothetically where the opposition is
actually antiational and they they they
parrot the propaganda of of outside
forces hypothetically in some countries
it may happen like that. So that's a
problem right if if that's the case for
for such countries it's it's a problem.
So in India it can only move towards
stability or or one party rule through
the democratic process. There's no other
way it can happen the way things
currently are unfortunately.
Hush has no question but thank you so
much sir. Thank you.
Naman Singh says I have observed that NR
are pro-Hinduism and not pro India. I
know many of these NRIs who go on X or
Twitter or whatever and they pro tweet
lots of pro-Hindu things. So nine tweets
will be pro- Hindu and one tweet will be
about India should do this this this
this and make Trump happy. I've seen
many NRAs like this. Trojan horses. If
you go to my Twitter feed and you will
you will see some images of Trojan
horses and then you will see who those
NRAs are. I don't know. Um I'm sure
there are many NR who are also pro-
India. Uh but the ones but there are
also a lot of Trojan horses there. So
that's how it is.
Okay,
Prashan says, "What are rare earth
minerals? How can India catch up?" Rare
earth minerals are rare uh rare
minerals. They are rare earth metals.
Okay. Uh let's let's quickly I don't
remember the exact name. Well, lithium
nedium.
Okay. Rare earth names
which are the elements scandium the 15
lanthnides.
See all these neody neodymium,
prometheium, samarium, europium,
gadolenium, turbium, disprosium,
holmium, aribbium, thulium, etherbium,
lute, luteesium, luteia, luteesium. So
these are the rare earth elements and
these are used in various technologies.
Okay, these are used in very high
techch. These are these metals are they
have very high-tech applications.
So when it comes to cell phones, there
are some very very minute components of
cell phones which need rare earth metals
or minerals and without these rare
earths, you you you won't have these
phones functioning. The same goes for uh
for microprocessors and and essentially
all high-tech equipment. So that's why
you need these rare earths and China
controls 90 95% of the rare earth supply
of the rare earths globally.
So how can India catch up? Well, India
also is a gigantic land mass and we also
have uh significant reserves of rare
earths. We definitely have enough rare
earths to become completely
self-sufficient in rare earths. But why
haven't we caught up yet? It's because
nobody has set up the mining and
extraction industries in India. That
takes time. That's pretty expensive.
So that's why we have been simply happy
to not do anything here and keep
importing from China. And then when
China decides that we will no longer
sell it to you, what happens? Haha.
That's what happens. So it is high time
once again for the government or whoever
it is to look into this very seriously
and set up the rare earths extraction
and um extraction and purification
industries in India. That's what needs
to happen. Yeah, it can happen in in a
few years, 5 10 years, it can happen.
Galler says for products that are made
in India if we label them as such and
this be made mandatory e either as
government policy or to the Supreme
Court su can the WTO oppose can WTO
oppose look look at what's happening in
the world right now Trump's tariffs
absolutely un unilateral tariffs which
is completely in violation of everything
the WTO stands for
so is the WTTO even relevant today
have they said a word against Trump. So
now that they are completely quiet and
silent and inactive when Trump is
unleashing a trade war on the world,
they better stay stay quiet when a
country like India does something that
is beneficial to our national interest.
So I think um I don't know about Supreme
Court and all that but I'm sure the
government policy can be such that if
products are made in India then they
should be labeled as such. I don't think
there's anything wrong with that. It's
it's an internal matter of India. we
decide our own policy and the WTO can
stay the hell away. So I think uh there
should be no issue and even if the WTO
tries to complain we can tell them where
where were you when Trump Trump was
doing all this he's still doing all of
this what have you said about this so if
you want to speak about that shut the
hell up about this that's what we can
say so uh I think this should be this
can be done and it's good it will be
good if if it's done so we know that
which products are actually been in
India and maybe patriotic people can
support those yeah
naman Singh says why is the US looking
like a clown these days no serious
Well, you see a nation,
the way a nation looks, a nation's image
depends on what? Well, to a large
extent, a nation's image depends on the
image of their leader.
Yeah. If the leader is a person with
with majesty, for example, or a person
with gravitas,
then the country looks like a serious
country. But if your leader is a joker,
well then your country looks like a
cloud. So you see, if your leader is not
serious, your country doesn't look
serious. You see, that's how it goes.
That also applies to sports teams. You
will see this phenomenon in sports. For
example, cricket. The entire team
eventually takes up the personality of
the captain. If your captain is a very
quiet, introverted person, the whole
team becomes like that. If your captain
is this brash, arrogant and and
aggressive person then the whole team
starts behaving like that. You will see
that when Gangoli was the captain the
whole team behaved like Ganguli. When
Dhoni was the captain, the whole team
behaved like Dhoni. And who is it? Who's
the captain now?
When when Kohli was captain, the whole
team behaved like that. And who is the
captain now? Ah, it's Gil. So yeah. So
you will see the whole team taking up
the the persona of Gil as well. So
that's how it goes. The leader makes a
huge difference. If the leader is a
joker, the country looks like a clown.
Kl Bora says, "Why do we suffer the
common people?" Well, it depends on
where you are. If you are in a super
rich country, you won't suffer. Or maybe
you will suffer in different ways.
Look, look, I'll tell you what. This
world is a world of Moaya.
Lord Buddha said that the world, what is
the one truth in the world? It is
suffering. Well, that's one way of
looking at the world. You can also have
a great amount of fun in the world and
do very meaningful things. But at the
end of the day, there is some suffering
in life. Okay? Everybody loses something
or other over time. As you grow older,
you'll find that lots of things that you
had in the past as a kid, as a
youngster, those are no longer there.
And then you feel a sense of loss. And
that's what happens. Suffering. And that
happens to common people. It happens to
uncommon people as well. Uh apart from
that, if you talking about the suffering
that's only reserved for common people,
well, that happens when you're in in a
third world country.
If you're in a first world country, the
the common people don't suffer so much.
So yeah.
Okay. Hayes says, "How when can India
reclaim P militarily?" Yeah, let's know.
At least once in a session, I get the
question of P. I I don't know, sir. I
don't know. Uh when can India reclaim P?
I I was hoping that Operation Synindur
will will end with P back with India,
but Trump came in the way. So I suppose
whenever India and Pakistan go to war
next which will happen sooner or later I
suppose we can end this once and for
all. Yeah because no victory is complete
without u an exchange of territory. We
hammered Pakistan hard in operation
Sindu the three-day war but we we did
not take any territory. If we had taken
even even half a kilometer of territory
okay then the world's media would have
been completely silent. So I think
whenever this war happens next which is
bound to happen now now that Trump is
behind is in the hot seat behind
Pakistan uh whenever that happens I
suppose there will be some exchange of
territory.
Rahul says Barat is buying more and more
crude oil from Russia. Are we heading
towards big scale war near the future?
Well I hope not but I think a war with
Pakistan could happen sooner or later
because the Americans want that to
happen. The Americans are very upset
about India not becoming an American
vasal and they want to contain India.
They have done so much in the past.
They've laid the groundwork for
containing India. They did a regime
change operation in in West Pakistan in
2022. Aster Imran Khan and Sharif is now
the so-called leader and they did a
regime change operation few months ago
in West in East Pakistan. They got rid
of Shik Kazina and brought in a military
government and they also started
operation project Kukan for Christ. Uh
the the the mayhem in Manipur that is
all done by them and they also have been
playing the game of uh subnational
diplomacy and dillydallying with various
political parties at various levels all
of that. So the Americans want to
contain India and one of the steps in
the containment policy will and if these
steps don't work and India still does
well then they will induce Pakistan to
go to war with India. So I think that
could be happening that could be coming
in I don't know in the coming days weeks
months whenever it happens it could
happen. uh beyond that I don't see any
big scale war. A war with Pakistan
probably will happen sometime but it may
not be a big scale war because uh that
would be hopefully a decisive war which
ends the headache for us the headache on
the western border once and for all.
Rail says could you share your insight
on the recent student worker protests in
Indonesia which articles suggesting a
revolution with articles suggesting a
revolution may be in progress. Well, I
haven't really kept a close watch on
this, but whenever these spontaneous
student protests happen
and the students are typically from very
affluent universities in very rich
backgrounds, it's generally
you would have seen that that sort of
thing happen in Thailand also in in in
recent years. So it's usually a sign to
the government
that is running the country that hey
you're getting out of line. Get back in
line and do what you're told. And that
message comes from Washington. Generally
it's to be understood. It is an implicit
message to the government that when
these students start protesting out of
nowhere
wellorganized students and all that
there's always somebody behind that a
very powerful entity behind that. So it
essentially is an indication. It's a
signal to the government of the country
that you better get back in line. You're
doing something that we don't like. Get
back in line and stop annoying us. Uh
yeah, I don't know if a re revolution
could be in process. If the government
doesn't get the hint, then a revolution
could happen. Yeah. Like what happened
in Bangladesh, it was not a student
revolution. It was a coup. Eventually at
the end of the day, the the military
comes in. That's how it goes. So yeah,
project smiling Buddha says, "Why are
Indians so afraid of loss in wars like
planes or men? Russia throws everything
into the war. We can't be powerful. If
you're so calculative, how to change
this?" It's because India Indians have
this mindset. If one aircraft is lost,
oh my god, we lost an aircraft. If a few
soldiers said, "Oh my god, boohoo." War
is like that.
You can't be a great country if you
don't have the appetite to to tolerate
some of this.
How many Americans died in second in the
Second World War? How many Americans
died in the Korean war? How many
Americans died in the Vietnam war? Did
they go raising a human who cry about
this? Did they go crying boohoo
everywhere all all over the place? And
their population is much smaller than
ours.
So the I I don't know what it is. It's
it's it's the fault of the education
system, the media, the entertainment
industry, all of that.
In war, you will have losses. Even if
you win, when the Americans destroyed
Iraq, how many soldiers did they lose?
How many aircraft did they lose? They
lost lots, but they won. And nobody was
complaining. But in India, we are a
nation of complainers.
The Russians have won so many wars. But
at what cost? But have they cried? Of
course, they honor their soldiers after
everything is over. They honor the the
soldiers who made the sacrifices, but
when when a war is going on, they are
they are not afraid to throw soldiers in
the fray and to throw equipment into the
fray. That's what you have to do in a
war. Without that, you you win nothing.
So, I don't know how to change this to
change things in India. If you want to
change the mindset of Indians, you have
to go back to the very basics and change
the whole education system. Without
changing the education system and
educating people about the very basics
at the earliest age, nothing will
change. Once somebody is 20, 25, what
will you change about them? You can
lecture them for 3 hours or 3 days,
nothing will change in their minds.
Right?
Satellite says, which form of government
has been most reliable and stable? the
imperial system, empires, emperors,
that's what been most most reliable and
stable historically over the past few
thousand years.
Dins said says I think India needs to
bring a scheme to bring back all wealthy
NRIs back to innovate and build
industries. How can this be done without
with India's low average wages? It can
be done
first of all by ending or or sharply
curtailing corruption in India. Secondly
by making India a completely fully
meritocratic country and society and
thirdly by by giving the right
inducements to people for which would
make them come back. How did China get
so many people back from the US? How did
China do that? By giving them worldclass
salaries. The government would guarantee
that that you will get the kind of
salary you will get nowhere else. You
come back to China, we will treat you
like royalty. You got to work hard.
You've got to you've got to produce the
goods. As long as you do that, we will
treat you like royalty. That's what
needs to happen. Then all the
highquality Indians will return to India
because India will be a different kind
of place then, right? It'll no longer be
a third rate mediocre country.
Okay. Milan says in Australia there's
this anti-immigration protest going on
and that turned into an anti-India
protest with pamphlets circulating
against Indians. Yes, that is the the
deal in the western world right now.
They are going after India. Indians are
the best immigrants anywhere in the
world. The model immigrants. Indians
work hard. They earn more than the
locals and they give more back to
society than the locals do. Indians
never do violence. Indians don't indulge
in crimes. Indians don't do to girls
what the Pakistanis do. We do none of
that. Right? And yet the hatred is being
is being is being unleashed on Indians.
That's what you're going to see more and
more. It's not because first of all
first of all it's a racist thing. The
whites have always been racist. at some
I'm not saying all white people are
racist but the Europeans have
historically been a racist society in
the past 500 days they've developed the
sense of superiority so if you are an
Indian in a in a western nation
Australia is a western nation even
though it's it's in Oceanania it's still
a western nation u you're going to be
treated well according to law you are
all equal citizens but kind of you're
going to be treated like a secondass
citizen in some ways uh in some ways in
some ways it'll It will be very subtle.
You may not realize it until you're
there for a long time. But you will see
there's some difference. And sometimes
it will come out very openly like this
in times such as these when the US is
going after India. The US is very upset
about India. Then you will see this sort
of hatred being unleashed against
Indians. So it's unfortunate. So I would
recommend to everybody all Indians,
Indian origin people in Australia or in
the western world to be a little alert.
Right.
Okay, we're going to do seven more
minutes. This is going to be a 60-minute
session, unfortunately. U it's a special
session. If you want, I can do another
60-minute session tomorrow as well. So,
that's not an issue, but I'm going to
have to end this at 5:45 p.m. IST.
Another 7 minutes. Let's take one more,
a few more. Prattab says, "Do RI
countries really shatter the West's
dominance?" They can if they actually
genuinely work together. Russia, India,
China, if they set differences aside.
See, India and Russia have no
differences. China and Russia have some
differences. India and China have huge
differences. If we can find a way to set
the differences aside and genuinely work
together in mutually beneficial ways,
then we will in a few years end the west
dominance. That is guaranteed. If the
forces of India, China, Russia combine
and work together, the west is finished
in a few years. It will happen. But the
question is how do India and China set
the differences aside? That's the big
problem right now.
Prashant says, "Uh, wish our PM could
sign EOS instead of the democratic way,
executive orders." Well, that would be
great, right? But then if you can just
govern through executive orders, well,
then you're essentially an emperor,
aren't you? Even if it's for 5 years,
yeah, it would be great. Then things
would get done so so much faster without
all the committees and all the consensus
and all all that nonsense and all the
voting and all the consultation with the
federal structure and all that. My
goodness, how slowing things are in
India if the PM could just sign EOS
executive orders and get things done
done. Imagine how fast India will
change. Yeah, one wishes.
Kumar Kanesk says as the US is picking a
fight with everyone on the basis of its
dollar being the reserve currency until
it is do you see the US sliding back to
post World War II position if things
continue like this this decade
well if the dollar loses its its uh
supremacy in the world if if if it
slides back and is no longer kind of the
the the reserve currency then the US
will slide back significantly.
uh
sliding back to preWorld War II or post
World War II, post World War II
position, the US's position post World
War II was sup super dominant. It was
super dominant. The the dollar was the
reserve currency in the world. It was
not under question the way it is today.
So,
so the US is fighting to preserve its
supremacy and to preserve the status of
the dollar as the reserve currency. That
is what the fight is about. Um, how are
things going this decade? I think more
and more countries are looking for
alternatives beyond the US dollar. even
India is if that continues then and if
the US is not able to stop that then
it's going to be bad times for for the
US because their whole uh
one of the one of the aspects of the
dominance is the US dollar's mind which
won't exist anymore
says will the
quizing will the word zalinski enter the
US dictionary as a synonym to traitor so
the synonym to traitor
since the second world war has been
Quizling. Quizling was the the leader of
which country? Sweden, Denmark, one of
these countries, right? And I believe he
was executed for treason for
collaborating with the Nazis. Let us
fact check that. Was he collab? Was he
executed?
Uh Quizling
Quiz
Quizling
Vick Vic Vickdun Quizling Norway who led
a collaborist collaborationist
government in German occupied Norway and
I believe he was eventually
if I'm not mistaken he was eventually
executed. He was executed. Yes. Trial
and execution. All right. So Quizling
was executed.
uh but you see for the so this word
quizzling entered the English dictionary
as as a synonym to traitor because he
was regarded as a traitor by the English
and by the west but zalinsky is a
collaborative collaborator with them
right so they won't use the word
zalinsky as as a synonym for traitor uh
they won't do it maybe others will so it
may enter maybe the Russian dictionary
as as a synonym synonym for traitor
maybe the Chinese dictionary as synonym
traitor but not the English dictionary
because he's collaborating with the
English speaking
Okay, I will take two three more
questions and then we're done. Mahar
says there have been a lot of attacks on
Indian immigrants and students in
western countries. We have been seeing a
lot of attacks in Ireland, Canada and
the US. What can we do to stop this?
There is nothing we can do to stop it.
We what can we do to stop it? Nothing.
All I can say to Indian immigrants who
are living there is be extra careful. Be
extra vigilant. things are no longer the
same. Okay? When you are in a place
where well a strange place, be be aware,
be awake, look around, look who's around
you, all of that you to see. There's
nothing we can do. The at the best what
we can do is we can have Prime Minister
Modi protest and urge the leaders of
these countries uh the leader of the US,
the leader of Canada, leader of Ireland
and leader of Australia to ensure that
Indian origin people uh their their
safety is taken care of. That's the best
Mr. Modi can do. That's the highest we
can do. Beyond that, there's nothing we
can do. So, I would say that look, if
you are an immigrant in these countries,
be careful. Be careful. Be very careful.
Says, have you read the book The Eye of
Shoe by Amiur?
It talks about how Indians whip be will
be the most likely to genetically edit
themselves. Wally, I want to check it
out. I haven't read it, but I will make
sure to check it out. The eye of Shiva
by Amori.
Okay, I'll check it out. Thank you for
the recommendation. Interesting.
Priya Bharat says, "Is living in the US
dangerous for Indians?" Look, the US is
a nation of laws. It's a very legalistic
nation and uh
overall law and order has kind of
deteriorated in the US and it's it's
it's possible that Indians could be
singled out by racist people uh for
violence perhaps. It's it's possible. I
think the likelihood is slightly higher
now. It doesn't mean it's it's dangerous
for Indians. Look, if you are a rich
person, living in the US is not
dangerous. As long as you take all the
precautions u but if you are not a rich
person and you living in a working-class
neighborhood, the likelihood is higher
that you may be in a slightly more
danger. Overall, it's it's still safe
for Indians. Um, and if you're attacked,
I'm sure you can you can go to the take
recourse in in the law of the land and
so on. My point is just be careful. I
think there is a higher likelihood right
now that people will go after Indians.
Overall, it's not been dangerous.
Historically, it's not been dangerous.
It's been a great place, but these days
things are different. Okay, two more
questions and we're done. MK says why
post nationalistic revolutions and
freedom struggle regimes didn't bring
violence at the scale of postcommunist
revolution regimes
see
postnationalistic revolutions freedom
struggle regimes were generally
nationalistic and they did not believe
in the dictatorship of the proletariat
and when you believe in the dictatorship
of the proletariat which Marxists do
then it is your duty to go after the
bourgeoisi and and and uh the reef what
what are they called the
that's there that's a term that I forget
right now okay it's a Marxist term I
haven't thought of it for a while so the
boogeoisi are the are the people who
need to be wiped out because they are
very naughty and very evil and they
amassed all the wealth they became
wealthy how dare you become wealthy so
when a Marxist revolution succeeds if
ever if ever does then once it succeeds
they go after the kulaks and and and and
the bourgeoisi
and uh whoever else. So that violence
continues in a post nationalistic
revolution or whatever things settle
down after the the revolution succeeds.
It's a totally different paradigm.
Nibbum says motorist unhappy with
ethanol. How will government fix it? I
have no idea. I have no idea. This is
not a geopolitical issue. I have no
idea. Sorry. Yeah. It's a it's a
domestic uh issue. I'm sure it's it's a
it's a problem in some ways. I I'm not
aware of the details, but yeah, I don't
have an answer to this question. All
right. Okay, folks. We have crossed the
1 hour mark. I'm going to have to end it
over here. Thank you so much for the
questions. Would you like me to to do
another live stream like this tomorrow?
1 hour. If you would like it, then I I
can I'll be happy to do it. Otherwise,
we can do it as as per our regular
programming on the weekends. Uh do let
me know in the comments or wherever. I
can see Bruce Wayne saying yes. Omni
movement is saying yes. Amisha saying
yes.
Animals for laugh is saying yes. Sadhart
Amisha Vladimir Putin Priyawat Sar
Chandra. Okay. Everybody is saying yes.
I'm going to have to do it. Geopolitical
dub also Aush also. Pritam.
All right. All right. I hear you all. We
shall do another 1 hour live stream
tomorrow. All right. So I'm going to
take your leave now. Thank you so much
and I look forward to seeing you in the
next live stream. Take care. Thank you.
See you soon. Bye-bye.